<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-07-29T12:04:57-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Neen Bean Research</title><subtitle>Neen Bean Research focuses on bringing you solutions to touch genealogy research problems.
</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;social&quot;=&gt;{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;jilleenp@gmail.com&quot;}}</name></author><entry><title type="html">When the Evidence Doesn’t Make Sense</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023-07-21-when_the_evidence_doesnt_make_sense/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When the Evidence Doesn’t Make Sense" /><published>2023-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-29T12:04:57-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/when_the_evidence_doesnt_make_sense</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023-07-21-when_the_evidence_doesnt_make_sense/"><![CDATA[<p>If you have a pile of records naming a person that you can’t make sense out of, there may be a very good reason for your confusion.</p>

<p>Meet the Sherwoods.</p>

<p>I had a pile of records naming John Sherwood of Connecticut and New York. I even had quite a few records naming both John and his wife Abigail. But I could make sense out of NONE of it. The records just didn’t correlate in a way that made John and Abigail make sense. The dates of the records suggested that they had lived over two hundred years and in two states simultaneously. And Abigail was either John’s wife or mother or perhaps no relation at all.</p>

<p>Until I found the Sherwood genealogy website which gave me a family structure that made sense (and that I would probably not arrived at from the records alone).<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>Here’s what that family looked like:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Abigail Sherwood (1770-1856) was the daughter of one John Sherwood (1731-1777). She also had a brother John Sherwood (1764-1852).</li>
  <li>Abigail’s husband was also named John Sherwood (about 1775-about 1864). He was the son of (yep) yet another John (1740-1825) and Abigail (1753-1829) Sherwood.</li>
  <li>And <em>that</em> John Sherwood (1740-1825) was also was the son of a John Sherwood (1703-1768).</li>
</ul>

<p>And all of those were unique individuals. Once I had a family structure in place and was able to identify the life spans of each person, I was able to identity which record belonged to which person.</p>

<p>Sometimes it helps to attack your problem from different angles when the evidence isn’t making sense.</p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Access needs to be requested, but this is an excellent collaborative site. Do your own research to verify the conclusions on the site, however. See <a href="https://www.sherwoodgenealogy.org">https://www.sherwoodgenealogy.org</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;social&quot;=&gt;{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;jilleenp@gmail.com&quot;}}</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="general" /><category term="tricks_and_traps" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you have a pile of records naming a person that you can’t make sense out of, there may be a very good reason for your confusion.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To Those Who Come After</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023-07-16-my_reason_why/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To Those Who Come After" /><published>2023-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-21T13:54:51-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/my_reason_why</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023-07-16-my_reason_why/"><![CDATA[<p>This is what I want you to know.</p>

<p>I know it looks a little bit crazy, to spend all this time digging up little bits of information about all those who came before me. And perhaps it is. But this is why I do it:</p>

<p>These people <em>were real</em>.</p>

<p>They lived and died and loved. They felt hope and fear and knew what it was to dream of possibilities. They were farmers and carpenters and blacksmiths and pebble polishers and jacks-of-all-trades. They raised families and moved across wilderness and cleared land and built homes and sometimes wondered where their next meal was going to come from. One built the cabinet that stands in Mom’s office; one was considered an “unusual woman with unique powers” and so was tried as a witch; one was deaf from a childhood injury but lived a full and happy life; one brought his family from bustling Glasgow to quiet Otsego county; one fought the Revolutionary War after it was dropped on his doorstep; one went south to fight the Confederates and left a piece of his soul there. Far too many of them have names I don’t even know.</p>

<p>But it’s only because of each one of them that I am here.</p>

<p>None of them was famous or rich or got their name in a history book. But their lives <em>mattered.</em> These people that I come from did great things in small ways, and because of them their families grew and their communities thrived and land was made livable. Nothing would be the same if it hadn’t been for the lives they lived.</p>

<p>And here’s the thing: if the lives of these simple farmers and overlooked women mattered, then <em>my</em> life matters, too. And so does yours. Remember that.</p>

<p>I take this time and do this work so that I can hear their stories and learn their lessons. I do this work because each of these people - these <em>lives</em> - are worth being remembered.</p>

<p>Jilleen Walch Phillips<br />
New York<br />
April 14, 2022</p>

<hr />

<blockquote>
  <p>“Suddenly all my ancestors are behind me. Be still, they say. Watch and listen. You are the result of the love of thousands.”<br />
― Linda Hogan, Dwellings: A Spiritual History of the Living World</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;social&quot;=&gt;{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;jilleenp@gmail.com&quot;}}</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="general" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is what I want you to know.]]></summary></entry></feed>